(Sheldon(entering):)Looking out at your fresh young faces...
(Sheldon(entering):)...I remember when I too
was deciding my academic future...
(Sheldon(entering):)...as a lowly graduate student.
(Sheldon(entering):)Of course, I was 14...
...and had achieved more
than you could ever hope to...
...despite my 9:00 bedtime.
(Sheldon(entering):)Now, there may be one or two of you
in this room who has what it takes...
(Sheldon(entering):)...to succeed in theoretical physics.
It's more likely that you will spend
your careers teaching fifth graders...
...how to make papier-mâché volcanoes
with baking-soda lava.
(Leonard:)Oh, good God.
(Sheldon:)In short, anyone who told you
that you would someday be able...
(Sheldon:)...to make any significant contribution
to physics played a trick on you.
(Sheldon:)A cruel trick indeed.
(Sheldon:)Any questions?
(Sheldon:)Of course not.
(Sheldon:)I weep for the future of science.
(Sheldon:)Now, if you'll excuse me,
the latest issue of Batman is out.
(Sheldon:)Come, Leonard.
(Leonard:)Laser demonstration's looking
pretty good now, huh?